Guide to the Faculty Records, 1911-1986 UA.28.01.0009
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Committee Records, 1930-1934
  Miscellaneous records, 1934-1947: Materials include agendas, reports, memoranda, questionnaires, and correspondence. Main topics include divisional committees, freshman and sophomore class size, class periods, class schedules, public lectures, examination periods, the grading system, junior and senior courses, and degree requirements. Additional topics also are grade distribution, "cuts," number of freshman, scholarship statistics, vacations, committee lists and nominees, advanced courses, the bookstore, student-faculty relations, the honor system, professional ethics, undergraduate publications, and research. Other issues addressed included transportation, curriculum problems, evaluations of admission, failure, and achievement, the Woman's College, holidays, naval training or the V-12 program, the library, athletics, cheating, and the honor code. Topics remain constant throughout the years. The Report of the Committee on "Adequate Student Guidance," (folder 6) represents an analysis of guidance methods as applicable to undergraduate liberal arts college. The report includes definitions, a needs assessment, and sections on areas of guidance, testing, counseling, and criteria for effective counseling. Tables include testing data for Duke freshman, analysis of personal problems, and reasons for academic difficulty, all based on data collected via questionnaires.
  C. Faculty Committee on the Teaching Load of Instructors, 1940
  Reports and minutes about the enrollment of students in various university departments are housed in this folder.
  D. Faculty Standing Committee on the Curricula, 1941-1946
  Materials include correspondence, minutes, reports, proposals, memoranda, and agendas. Topics are degree program requirements, administration of curricula, guidance, admission requirements, honors, fellowships, freshman advisors, and academic probation. Note: Folders 19-20 contain the loose materials, dated 1911-1923, from the bound volumes of the Minutes of the General Faculty Meetings, Trinity College.
  E. Commission on Faculty Reorganization, 1951-1952
  Materials include agendas, correspondence, meeting minutes, and reports. A report on the chronology of the committee's work and an investigating sub-committee report are housed here.
  F. Faculty Organization Committee, 1951-1962
  Document types: reports with cover letters. The contents of this folder include a 1951 Report of the Commission on Faculty Reorganization to the General Faculty of Duke. It lists and discusses the chronology of the commission's work, and includes recommendations for the University Faculty, the University Council, the Undergraduate Faculty Council, the graduate school faculty, the engineering faculty school, and the faculties of the professional schools. This report also includes alternative plans for selecting members of the University Council. The additional two reports dated 1962 deal with the same issue in a similar way, and include cover letters.
  - Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Minutes (v.), 1934-1941 (Box 6)
  - Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Minutes, 1941-1949 (Box 6)
  - Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Miscellaneous, 1934-1935 (Box 6)
  - Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Miscellaneous, 1935-1936 (Box 6)
  - Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Miscellaneous, 1937-1979 (Box 6)
  - Council on Undergraduate Teaching-Committee Report, undated (circa 1930s) (Box 6)
  - Faculty-Committee on the Teaching Load of Instructors, 1940 (Box 6)
  - Faculty-Standing Committee on the Curricula, 1941-1946 (Box 7)
  - Faculty-Standing Committee on the Curricula-Chairman, 1941-1942 (Box 7)
  - Faculty-Standing Committee on the Curricula-Secretary, 1941-1942 (Box 7)
  - Commission on Faculty Reorganization, 1951-1952 (Box 7)
  - Faculty Organization Committee, 1962 (Box 7)
- Mailings and Miscellaneous Records, 1930-1979
  Miscellaneous memoranda, reports, notes, and other records apparently distributed to the faculty, 1940-1979. Materials include correspondence, newspaper clippings, announcements, memoranda, invitations, minutes, and reports. Topics include: applying for grants, the Academic Senate, new degree programs, honoraria, faculty publications, freshman concerns, family educational rights, international students, regulations for final exams and honor systems, degree candidate lists, post-war international problems, salary, commencement, long-range planning, the Woman's Student government Association, Bylaws, University Religious Council, segregation, attendance policies for undergraduates, and cooperative arrangements between Duke and UNC. Another subject involves the appointments of the University Executive Committee, the various departments, new faculty members and tenured faculty.
  - Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1930-1953 (Box 7)
  - Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1954-1963 (Box 7)
  - Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1964-1974 (Box 7)
  - Faculty-Miscellaneous records, 1975-1979 (Box 7)